Okay, in this clip, we're going to, I'm going to show you how to portion the fish.
This is a lot of fish.
This filet probably weighs about three pounds.
Okay?
You can't eat that much fish.
One person won't be served this much fish.
So we're going to take the fish and we're going to cut it into, what I would consider equal portions.
Maybe what a chef would do in a restaurant and that's how they would serve it to you.
Okay, the fish is not even as far as thickness.
You have got the tail portion, the head portion and you have the thickness mainly in the middle.
So what usually happens is they're going to take a relatively smaller section off the tail.
And you're going to get about a six to eight ounce portion maybe is a good serving for someone.
And that?s a pretty, pretty uniform thickness.
A little tapered off in the tail, but it's a pretty uniform thickness.
That will be one serving.
What I always like to do is cut down the middle of the fish to basically split the rest of the filet in half.
You can see it's pretty thick, there's about a good inch and a half thick.
A lot of chefs are going to butterfly this open in some direction where you can still have a thinner piece of fish and they can get more out of their servings that way.
Okay.
Now, you basically have twice as much fish, half as thick.
And you know could cut that in half and these would be two more portions.
And this is not by any means exactly accurate the way you're going to get it.
A thicker filet, once again, I'm going to cut it straight down.
Very thick filet, hard to cook evenly.
We're going to try to, just cut this butterfly this open to get two filets out of this.
Two more filets.
Okay?
Do the same thing in the head area.
And you don't really want to waste anything because this fish is not cheap.
Natural resources getting harder and harder to come by.
So, we are going to leave as much fish on here and throw as little away as we can.
We want to sell this whole fish.
We want to eat this whole fish.
And now, we have two more filets.
So out of one side, I believe I got six filets, six portions.